Welcome back. In this video,
欢迎回来 在这个视频中
we'll briefly recap how sequence to sequence models work.
我们将简单总结下序列到序列模型的原理
A sequence to sequence model takes in an input that is a sequence of items,
序列到序列模型会接受一个条目序列作为输入
and then it produces another sequence of items as an output.
然后生成另一个条目序列作为输出
In a machine translation application,
在机器翻译应用中
the input sequence is a series of words in one language,
输入序列是一种语言的单词系列
and the output is the translation in another language.
输出是另一种语言的翻译
In text summarization, the input is a long sequence of words,
在文本摘要中 输入是一个很长的句子
and the output is a short one.
输出是很短的句子
A sequence to sequence model usually consists of an encoder and a decoder,
序列到序列模型通常由编码器和解码器组成
and it works by the encoder first processing all of
工作原理是编码器首先处理所有输入
the inputs turning the inputs into a single representation,
将输入变成一个表示结果
typically a single vector.
通常是一个向量
This is called the context vector,
称之为语境向量
and it contains whatever information the encoder
包含编码器能够从输入句子中
was able to capture from the input sequence.
获取的所有信息
This vector is then sent to the decoder which uses it to formulate an output sequence.
然后将这个向量发送给解码器 后者使用该向量形成输出句子
In machine translation scenarios,
在机器翻译场景中
the encoder and decoder are both recurrent neural networks,
编码器和解码器都是循环神经网络
typically LSTM cells in practice,
通常是 LSTM 单元
and in this scenario,
在这个场景中
the context vector is a vector of numbers encoding
语境向量是一个数字向量
the information that the encoder captured from the input sequence.
表示编码器从输入句子中获取的信息
In real-world scenarios, this vector can have a length of 256 or 512 or more.
在现实中 这个向量的长度会达到 256 或 512 或更高
As a visual representation,
为了用图形表示
we'll start showing the hidden states as this vector of length four.
我们将隐藏状态显示为这个长度为 4 的向量
Just think of the brightness of the cells corresponding to
将单元格的亮度看做
how high or low the value of that cell is.
该单元格的值高低程度
Let's look at our basic example again,
再来看看我们的基本示例
but this time we will look at the hidden states of the encoder as they develop.
但是这次将查看编码器的隐藏状态
The first step, we process the first word and generate a first hidden state.
第一步是处理第一个单词并生成第一个隐藏状态
Second step, we take the second word in the first hidden state as inputs to the RNN,
第二步是将第一个隐藏状态中的第二个单词当做 RNN 的输入
and produce a second hidden state.
生成第二个隐藏状态
In the third step,
在第三步
we process the last word and generate the last hidden state.
处理最后一个单词并生成最后一个隐藏状态
This is the hidden state that would be the context vector will send to the decoder.
这个隐藏状态将是发送给解码器的语境向量
Now, this here is the limitation of sequence to sequence models.
现在就要介绍序列到序列模型存在的限制
The encoder is confined to sending
无论输入句子有多长
a single vector no matter how long or short the input sequence is.
编码器都只能发送一个向量
Choosing a reasonable size for this vector
如果为这个向量选择合理的大小
makes the model have problems with long input sequences.
则在处理很长的输入句子时 模型会遇到问题
Now, one can say, let's just use a very large number of hidden units in the encoder,
你可能会说 要不在编码器中使用大量隐藏单元
so that the context is very large.
使语境很庞大
But then your model overfits with short sequences,
这样的话 模型在短句子上会过拟合
and you take a performance hit as you increase the number of parameters.
当你增加参数数量时 会遇到性能瓶颈
This is the problem that attention solves.
注意力可以解决这种问题